Guide to the Alan Klein Papers ca. 1980-1995 MSS 118 MSS.118
Fales Library and Special Collections
Alan Klein Papers
ca. 1980-1995
Fales Library and Special Collections
Klein, Alan
MSS.118
4.5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
The Alan Klein Papers represent Klein's, a New York based public relations consultant and long-time gay activist, collection of materials that chronicle the Gay-rights movement. The collection includes correspondence, flyers, periodicals, press clippings, T-shirts and other materials which focus on the activities of Act Up (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), and Queer Nation, among others.
Provenance
The Alan Klein Papers were purchased in 2001 from Bolerium Books.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note:
Alan Klein, a New York based public relations consultant, has been a long-time gay activist and was recently the Communications Director at the Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation (GLAAD). He collected these materials which chronicle the gay-rights struggle through the 1980's and early 1990's.
Scope and Content Note
The Alan Klein Papers are a part of the Downtown Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU Libraries, housing nearly 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel, and the post-1975 Downtown New York scene.
The Alan Klein Papers are a diverse collection of materials, including correspondence, fact sheets, flyers, healthcare reports, minutes, periodicals, press clippings, T-shirts and other materials, which collectively document the activities of Act Up (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power) and Queer Nation, as well as the social and political issues central to their causes. Throughout the processing of these papers, Klein's original folder groupings and titles were maintained as much as possible. These folders were then filed alphabetically under the series titles Act Up, Queer Nation, AIDS, and General Files based on the content of their materials.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into six series.
Missing Title
Series I: Act Up
Series II: Queer Nation
Series III: AIDS
Series IV: General Files
Series V: Periodicals
Series VI: T-Shirts
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials but that have been physically separated or removed.
Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; AIDS (Disease) and mass media.; T-shirts; Gay liberation movement.; Reports.; Official reports.; New York (N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease) |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Magazines (Periodicals); Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); United States. Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic; ACT UP (Organization); Klein, Alan; Queer Nation (Organization)
- Series I: Act Up
  - Action Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Act Now, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Act Now-Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Act Up Report, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Files (Calendars, Agendas, Proposals), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AIDS Drugs Now, 5/2/1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Albany March, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chapters (other than New York City)-Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Church Action-Stop the Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contact Lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Coordinating Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coordinating Committee Proposals, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Did You See?" Files, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Election 1988-Clippings (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fact Sheets re: Other Groups, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - FDA Action, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Features re: Act Up, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Features re: Act Up-Radical America, vol. 20, no. 6, Nov./Dec. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Gay Freedom Ride, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gay Pride '89, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General (Membership Packet, Minutes, Proposals, Administrative Files), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Housing Issues re: People with AIDS (PWAs), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Leaflets, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Leaflets (Other Groups), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Media Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Media Committee Press Releases, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Montreal International Conference on AIDS, June 1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Montreal Manifesto-A National AIDS Treatment Research Agenda, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - National March on Washington, October 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - New Jersey Chapter, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - New Jersey Chapter, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - New Jersey Chapter-Outcry, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - New York City, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - New York Post Editorial by Karl Soehn re: Article Entitled "The Man Who Gave Us AIDS", undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Outreach Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Republican and Democratic Conventions, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Speakers Bureau Subcommittee, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Target City Hall, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Target City Hall: An AIDS Activist's Guide to New York City in 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Target City Hall-Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Target City Hall-Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Target City Hall-Mayor Ed Koch's Response, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Target City Hall-Press Packets, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wall Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wall Street-Criminal Court Case, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wall Street-Criminal Court Case, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Weekly Reports, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Zaps/Actions, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series II: Queer Nation
  - Chronology, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Contacts, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Demonstrational Graphic Designs, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Flyers and Fact Sheets, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes/Agendas, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Press Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series III: AIDS
  - Addiction (Drugs), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Advocates-Pride Guides, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - American Foundation for AIDS Research, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Antibody Testing-Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Art and AIDS, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Articles, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ATEU (AIDS Treatment Evaluation Units), undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Community Based Clinical Trials, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Demonstrational Graphic Designs, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Demonstrational Graphic Designs, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Discrimination, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Discrimination-Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Education, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Education-Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Editorials, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Experimental Drugs, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Experimental Drugs, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Gays and the Catholic Church, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - General Information, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - General Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Global Perspective-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Glossary of AIDS Drug Trials, Testing, and Treatment Issues, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Healthcare Reports, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Healthcare System-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - HIV Antibody Testing, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - HIV/Syphilis Connection-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - IV Drug Use-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Klein, Alan. AIDS and the Media for the AIDS Seminar, 12/17/1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Legislation, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Legislation-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Media-Critiques of Media Representation of AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meyers, Woody-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minorities and AIDS-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Name Project Quilt, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - New York City AIDS Budget, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Presidential Commission on AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Presidential Commission on AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Presidential Commission on AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Press Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Prevention, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Prison-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Quarantine/Drastic Measures--Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Report of the Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, 6/1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Right-wing Reaction-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Spending Budgets City/Federal, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Spending/Funding-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - St. Patrick's-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Television and AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Transmission-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Treatment/Care-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Treatment and Data Updates, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Treatment Facts, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Women and AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Women and AIDS, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Women and AIDS-Handbook, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Series IV: General Files
  - Civil Rights/Federal Government-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Domestic Partnership-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Gay Rights/Homophobia, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gay Rights/Homophobia-Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Klein, Alan-Personal Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Klein, Alan-Resume, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Outing Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Notebook-Labeled "Jewish American Writers", undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Notebook-Labeled "Pop Culture", undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Note Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Series V: Periodicals
  - The Advocate: no. 455, 7/16/1986 no. 461, 12/9/1986 no. 557, 9/14/1990., 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Artforum International, Oct. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Capital Gay, no. 415, 10/20/1989. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Guardian Supplement on Lesbian and Gay Liberation. Summer, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gay Community News: vol. 15, no. 4, Aug. 2-8, 1987, vol. 15, no. 27, Jan. 24-30, 1988, vol. 15, no. 31, Feb. 21-27, 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gay Community News: vol. 15, no. 40, April 24-May 7, 1988, vol. 16, no. 13, Oct. 9-15, 1988, vol. 16, no. 47, Jun. 18-24, 1989 vol. 17, no. 48, Jun. 24-30, 1990, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Face, no. 98, June, 1988. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The New Common Good. 4/1988. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsweek: 1/13/1986, 8/10/1987, 3/12/1990., 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New Youth Connections, Dec., 1987. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New York: 8/11/1986, 5/14/1990, 11/12/1990, 2/17/1992., 1986-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Next, vol. 1, no. 48, 11/16/1988. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Outrage, no. 63, Aug., 1988. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - People, 11/5/1990. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Queers, Read This, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Rolling Stone, no. 483, 9/25/1986; no. 573, 3/8/1990., 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Spin vol. 3, no. 7, Nov.-Dec., 1987 vol. 4, no. 10, Jan., 1989., 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Volunteer, vol. 3, no. 6, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series VI: T-Shirts
  - Five T-Shirts, undated (Box 6, Folder data_value_missing_44b8e6b04a9b93eaa5f34e34cb2991cb)